[Music]
it's been said that the only thing that
stops a bad microbiome is a good
microbiome the question is how to
establish that healthy gut Flora there's
a multi-billion dollar industry pushing
probiotic supplements but despite
thousands of clinical trials we like our
microbiome are left largely in the dark
when researchers analog the first 150
results that Google pulled up on
probiotics commercial sites were the
most common which provided on average
the least reliable information most of
the claimed benefits were found to be
supported by little or no scientific
evidence a recent systematic review of
randomized controll Trials of probiotic
supplements for healthy older adults
found there was insufficient evidence
for the Improvement of Health outcomes
for example probiotics don't appear to
work for TM AO reduction or improve
cognition in dementia patients what can
they do various probiotic preparations
have been found to improve stool
consistency bowel movement frequency and
abdominal bloating as well as reduce the
incidence of antibiotic Associated
diarrhea outside of the gut one strain a
type of lactobac cells was found to
accelerate the healing of wrist
fractures in the elderly and improve
hand function recovery though the best
evidence for extraintestinal effects
involves the immune system even just a
few weeks to months of probiotic
supplementation can improve the
abilities of our immune cells to destroy
pathogens and cancer cells compared to
Placebo does this translate into reduced
infection rates on average older adults
suffer between 2 to five infectious
episodes a year including infections the
respiratory tract digestive tract and
urinary tract a metaanalysis of more
than a dozen randomized control trials
involving more than 5,000 older adults
average age 75 found no overall effect
on the occurrence or duration of
infections from probiotic
supplementation however by lumping all
infections together more finely tuned
effects might get washed out and indeed
looking more closely probiotics seem to
help reduce the instance duration and
symptoms of the common cold but failed
show any influence on the incidence or
severity of the
flu similarly how can metaanalyses make
sweeping statements about the efficacy
or failure of quote unquote probiotics
when each of the studies used different
types and combinations of bacteria
perhaps some work but the positive
signal is just lost in the noise there
are even studies showing that two
different strains of the exact same
species of bacteria can have different
effects what are the downsides of giving
some a try we don't have good data on
potential harms either isolated accounts
have been published of serious adverse
effects from probiotics that appear
independent of dose or formulation but
the great majority of clinical trials
have not reported major hazards
unfortunately an analysis of hundreds of
Trials found harms reporting was often
missing insufficient or inadequate which
undermines our confidence in the safety
of these supplements for for example
there concerns about antibiotic
resistance probiotics are often
intentionally selected to be antibiotic
resistant so they can be co-administered
with antibiotics to reduce diarrhea
rates but may transfer that resistance
to pathogens in our gut a study of
commercial probiotic supplements from
around the world including the United
States found all batches were resistant
to vanoy one of our hail Mery
antibiotics of Last Resort
the irony is that probiotics can
actually interfere with microbiome
recovery after antibiotics rather than
facilitate it without probiotics
spontaneous postantibiotic recovery back
to Baseline was found to occur within 3
weeks in contrast the microbiomes of
those randomized to take probiotics
remained off-kilter even 6 months later
the most rapid reconstitution occurred
in those given Auto feal
transplants just as it may be wise to
bank your own blood before an elective
procedure should you need a transfusion
those saving their own stool before
course of antibiotics were able to
restore their microbiomes back to normal
within a matter of
[Music]
days